healthyhearing.com 2013-06-30

# Healthy Hearing Privacy Policy

### About This Privacy Policy and Using Our Site and Tools

This Privacy Policy applies to the HealthyHearing.com website. The HealthyHearing.com website contains links to other sites. Once you enter another website (whether through an advertisement, service, or content link), be aware that HealthyHearing.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website you visit through a link or advertisement on HealthyHearing.com.

While you may use much of HealthyHearing.com without registration, some of the specific tools and services on our website require registration. If you use our website without registering, the only information we collect will be Non-Personal Information through the use of Cookies. If you choose to register with our website for educational courses or other services, we require you to submit Personally Identifiable Information. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to HealthyHearing.com. Inaccurate information will affect the information you receive when using our site and tools and our ability to contact you as contemplated in this Privacy Policy. For example, your email address should be kept current because that it is how we communicate with you.

### Non-Personal Information We Collect About You

Even if you do not register with HealthyHearing.com, we collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our website, special promotions and newsletters.

#### Cookies

We collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our website and your use of the websites of selected corporate partners and advertisers through the use of Cookies. Every computer is assigned a different Cookie by HealthyHearing.com. The information collected by Cookies (i) helps us dynamically generate advertising and content on web pages or in newsletters, (ii) allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our website and selected corporate partners' and advertisers' sites, (iii) how many people open our emails, and (iv) for what purposes these actions are being taken. We may use Cookie information to target certain advertisements to your browser or to determine the popularity of certain content or advertisements. Cookies are also used to facilitate a user's log-in, as navigation aides and as session timers.

Your browser software can be set to reject all Cookies. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject our Cookies, certain functions and conveniences of our website may not work properly but you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to productively use our site. We do not link Non-Personal Information from Cookies to Personally Identifiable Information without your permission.

### Identifiable Information We Collect About You

We collect Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us when you register as a member of HealthyHearing.com and/or when you update your member profile. We use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to respond to your questions, provide you the specific services you select, send you emails about website maintenance and updates, and inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy.

#### Newsletters & Emails to You

At registration and at various times as you use HealthyHearing.com, you will be given the option of receiving recurring informational/promotional newsletters via email from HealthyHearing.com and/or directly from third parties. At the time you sign up for our email newsletters or any time thereafter, you can choose to Opt-out of receiving additional promotional emails from HealthyHearing.com.

In order to subscribe to such newsletters via email, we need your contact information, such as name and email address. You can unsubscribe from the newsletters by simply clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email newsletter. An email to our automated unsubscribe service will be created on your computer. Click the "send" button. You will then be unsubscribed from that newsletter within two to three business days. You may also unsubscribe or change any of your email preferences by clicking on the applicable links in your email newsletter or by changing your profile within HealthyHearing.com. If you are experiencing difficulties with our automated unsubscribe service, you can email HealthyHearing.com Customer Service at webmaster@healthyhearing.com. HealthyHearing.com Customer Service will unsubscribe you from that newsletter in two to three business days.

In some cases, when you click on a link or an advertisement in an e-mail or newsletter, your browser may be momentarily directed to the website of a third party which, acting on behalf of HealthyHearing.com (see Disclosure to Website Service and Content Contractors, below), notes or "counts" your response to the e-mail or newsletter before re-directing your browser to its proper destination; this re-direction process will not be apparent to you.

When you use HealthyHearing.com's "Email a Friend" function, HealthyHearing.com emails the article or other content you designate to your friend's email address and lists your email address as the sender. HealthyHearing.com uses the friend's email address only for the purpose of sending your friend the email you requested. While we store both email addresses, we do not use them for any other purpose unless disclosed to you at the time you send the email.

#### Emails You Send to HealthyHearing.com

This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you send content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions to HealthyHearing.com by email. If you want to keep content or business information, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an email to HealthyHearing.com. We try to answer every email within 48 business hours, but are not always able to do so.

#### Chat Rooms and other Public Forums

As a service to our users, HealthyHearing.com features chat and eSeminar rooms and other public forums where users with similar interests or medical conditions can share information and support one another or where users can post questions for experts to answer. We also offer online discussions moderated by medical or healthcare experts.

Any information shared (including Personally Identifiable) that you reveal in a chat room, message board, "Ask The Expert" posting or "User Story/Testimonial" or online discussion is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service. You should think carefully before disclosing any Personally Identifiable or Personal Health Information in any public forum. What you have written may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes.

#### Market Research

From time to time the HealthyHearing.com market research department, or its operations contractors acting on its behalf, conducts online research surveys in order to gather feedback about our site, our corporate partners and opinions on important healthcare issues, through email invitations, pop-up surveys and online focus groups.

When participating in a survey, we may ask you to submit Personally Identifiable Information. This Personally Identifiable Information is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. When a survey is sponsored by a third party, Aggregate Information of the survey results is reported to the sponsor. Personally Identifiable Information collected through market research will only be used by HealthyHearing.com and its operations contractors and will not be given or sold to a third party without your consent.

In addition to collecting survey responses from our members, Cookies may be used to authenticate respondents or to help you pick up where you left off in a survey. If you have Cookies disabled you may not be able to participate in some studies. Cookies may be used to connect survey data with HealthyHearing.com site usage characteristics. You will be notified when we would like to use Cookies in this way and your consent will be requested for these Cookies.

#### Information Collected by Third Parties Not Acting on HealthyHearing.com's Behalf

Corporate Partners or advertisers on HealthyHearing.com may use their own Cookies in the banner advertisements served on HealthyHearing.com and in emails, special promotions or newsletters we send you. Some advertisers use companies other than HealthyHearing.com to serve their ads and to monitor users' responses to ads, and these companies ("Ad Servers") may also collect Non-Personal Information through the use of Cookies on our website. In certain situations, information collection may be facilitated by momentarily directing your browser to the website of an Ad Server or other third party acting on behalf of the corporate partner, or advertiser before re-directing your browser to its proper destination (e.g., back to HealthyHearing.com to show the ad, or to the advertiser's website); this re-direction process will not be apparent to you.

We do not control these third parties' use of Cookies, or how they manage the Non-Personal Information they gather through them. However, we do require corporate partners, advertisers and Ad Servers who collect Cookie information through our website to agree that they will not collect any Personally Identifiable Information from our website without your consent. They have promised us they will not link any Non-Personal Information collected by them through Cookies in advertising banners on our website to Personally Identifiable Information they or others collect. Certain Ad Servers allow you to prevent them from collecting data through the use of Cookies. In order to do so, you must Opt-out of such data collection with each individual site. Currently, you can Opt-out of Cookies for several Ad Servers by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative gateway Opt-out site. This website will also allow you to review the Ad Server's privacy policies.

### Disclosure of Your Information

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, HealthyHearing.com will not disclose any Personally Identifiable Information it gathers from you on our website. We will only release Personally Identifiable Information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; (2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others (3) to comply with arrangements made with our corporate partners as it relates to both live and pre-recorded e-learning courses. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. In addition, we may disclose Personal Information as described below.

#### Disclosure to Third Party Organizations for e-Learning Courses

For your convenience there are links to e-learning modules hosted by HealthyHearing.com, but managed and operated by companies and organizations other than HealthyHearing.com ("Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations"). These Third Party Companies and Organizations provide content or services, including e-learning courses through our website. These e-learning module links may be found in advertisements, referenced within content, or placed beside the names or logos of Corporate Partners. HealthyHearing.com will disclose limited Personal Information to these Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations as it relates to e-learning courses provided by a specific Third Party Corporate Partner. (Example - if a person registers for a particular e-learning course provided by Corporate Partner "A" then HealthyHearing.com will provide Corporate Partner "A" with limited Personally Identifiable Information as it relates to the course and the course participant. HealthyHearing.com does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these organizations. If you choose to participate in an e-learning course using one of these Third Party Company or Organization e-learning modules, you should review the privacy policy posted by this other company or organization to understand how that Third Party Organization collects and uses your Personally Identifiable Information.

#### Disclosure to Third Party Organizations for HAPPYTM

The Hearing Aid Personalized Profile for YouTM (HAPPYTM) is an opportunity for you to submit Personally Identifiable Information to HealthyHearing.com. HealthyHearing.com uses this information to construct a customized selection of information that is then sent to you in an unencrypted email. Once this information is submitted, and as you continue to browse and use HealthyHearing.com you have the opportunity to share this information with by companies and organizations other than HealthyHearing.com ("Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations"). When viewing information related to Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations, a form or link will be provided asking if you would like to share your HAPPYTM profile information with said Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations. If you agree to share this information, it will be sent to said Third Party Corporate Partner Companies and Organizations via unencrypted email. If you do not want to have your Personally Identifiable Information shared in this way, do not fill out the HAPPYTM online profile and discontinue use of HealthyHearing.com.

#### Disclosure of Aggregate Information

HealthyHearing.com may provide Aggregate Information to third parties. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of our website and the activities they conduct while on our site. We might also inform a company (that may or may not be an advertiser on our site) that "30% of our users live east of the Mississippi" or that "25% of our users dispense hearing aids." Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this Aggregate Information. We require parties with whom we share Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable, such as by combining it with other databases.

### How HealthyHearing.com Handles Privacy and Security Internally

Listed below are some of the security procedures that HealthyHearing.com uses to protect your privacy:

  * Requires both a personal username and a password in order for users to access their Personally Identifiable Information.
  * Uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers.
  * Utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting Personally Identifiable Information to our servers. In order to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an Internet browser which supports 128-bit encryption.
  * Closely monitors the limited number of HealthyHearing.com employees who have potential access to your Personally Identifiable Information.
  * Requires all HealthyHearing.com employees to abide by our Privacy Policy and be subject to disciplinary action if they violate it.
  * Backs-up our systems to protect the integrity of your Personally Identifiable.

Despite HealthyHearing.com's efforts to protect your Personally Identifiable Information and Personal Health Information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted.

### Updating Your Information and Contacting HealthyHearing.com

#### Updating Your Personally Identifiable Information 

HealthyHearing.com tools that collect and store self-reported data allow you to correct, update or review information you have submitted by going back to the specific tool, logging-in and making the desired changes.

#### Removing your Personal Information

If you have a complaint or problem, please email us at webmaster@healthyhearing.com. Our customer service department will forward your complaint to the appropriate internal HealthyHearing.com department for a response or resolution. We try to answer every email within 48 business hours, but we may not always able to do so. If you want to (1) delete your Personally Identifiable Information from our systems, (2) update the Personally Identifiable Information that you have provided to us, or (3) change your preferences with respect to marketing contacts or other activities; please email us at [webmaster@healthyhearing.com](mailto:webmaster@healthyhearing.com?subject=Privacy+Policy).

If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy related problem, you may write to HealthyHearing.com's Privacy Help Desk at:

Healthy Hearing  
PO Box 515381 #42919  
Los Angeles, CA 90051-6681  
T: 800 567 1692

#### Limitations on Removing or Changing Information

Upon your request, we will delete your Personally Identifiable from our active databases and where feasible from our back-up media. You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to HealthyHearing.com from our servers.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Personally Identifiable Information - We will inform you if a material change to the Privacy Policy is made that involve the use of your Personally Identifiable Information. Your continued use of the HealthyHearing.com website will indicate acceptance of the changes. You may of course choose to Opt-out of continuing to use the website. Please exit the site immediately if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy.
